Guide to the Sam Kim Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Sam Kim Collection
1966-1978
AOB 43
Yale University Arts Library
0.83
(2 boxes)
The collection showcases the wide variety of materials designed by Sam Kim, including annual reports, corporate stationery, greeting cards, bumper stickers, and T-shirts.
Kim, Sam
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Yale School of Art.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Sam Kim graduated from the Yale School of Art Graphic Design program, Class of 1964. He worked in Hawaii from 1964 to 1977. Upon Kim's death, the Yale School of Art organized a retrospective exhibition with examples of Kim's work selected by his classmates.
Scope and Contents
The collection showcases the wide variety of materials designed by Kim, including annual reports, corporate stationery, greeting cards, bumper stickers, and T-shirts.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Clients, 1966-1977. II. Personal, 1969-1978.
Commercial art -- United States -- 20th Century; Graphic arts; Printed ephemera
- Clients, 1966-1977; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by the name of the client.
  - American Growth Corp., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Properties Corp., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Avant Garb, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Barton, Clare H., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bishop Trust Co. LTD, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Blair, Russ, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bobbie Lee and Associates, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Center for Korean Studies at the University of Hawaii, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chung Dho Ahn & Associates, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cinerama Hotels, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Citizens for Hawaii, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Construction Control Corp., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Environment Impact Study Corp., undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - First West Engineering, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fukunaga & Associates, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Gill Family, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Globe Electric, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Gushman Land Company, LTD, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hawaii Committee for the Humanities, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Honolulu Redevelopment Agency, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Honolulu Symphony Society, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Innovative Media Incorporated, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Jon Okudara Photographics, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kahala Hilton, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Kauai Toyota, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kooliana, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Korean Doll Night Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - League of Women Voters of Hawaii, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Manufacturer's Products, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Marilyn Oka, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Mayor's Symphony Ball, Feb. 22, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Michael T. Suzuki and Associates, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Moiliili-McCully, Uwaine, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Noguchi, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Oka Landscaping, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Oka Nursery, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Pacific Gallery & Art Supplies, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Phil & Charles Gregory Associates, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Pico Jr., Tom, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Pono Development Company, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Sakau South Pacific, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Sam Kim Designs, 1969 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Sam Kim Designs, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Small Business Educators, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - State of Hawaii: Office of the Ombudsman, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - State of Hawaii: Office of the Ombudsman, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - State of Hawaii: Office of the Ombudsman, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - State of Hawaii: State Fair, 1973 1974 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Sun Investment Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Te-Noe, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Thomas Square Plaza Medical Associates, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Transco Hawaii Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Trends of Hawaii, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - 20th Century Furniture, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Wilson & Bartlett, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Yap, Ted, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Youth Caucus: Steering Committee, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Unidentified: Photo of T-Shirts, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Unidentified: Year of the Pig, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Unidentified: Year of the Tyger T-Shirt, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Unidentified: Year of the Rabbit T-Shirt, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Unidentified: Year of the Dragon T-Shirt, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Unidentified: Year of the Snake T-Shirt, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Personal, 1969-1978; Series II
  - Kim, Sam: Family, 1969 undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Kim, Sam: Personal, 1978 undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Label from box containing exhibition materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 64)